ASUDA RESIDENCE
（阿須田家）
KEIICHI NAGIKO
（惠一、止子）
YUI KAKERU
（結、翔）
KAITO KII
（海斗、希衣）
How is the weather today?
今天的天氣如何呢？
Good morning.
各位早安
Today will be a sunny day. Not a single cloud in sight.
今天會是萬里無雲的好天氣
It may feel a little warm with the sunlight,
雖然在陽光照射下會稍微回暖
but the temperature today will just be at 13 degrees Celsius.
但氣溫還是只有攝氏13度
When the wind blows from the north…
風從北邊吹過來時…
Good morning.
早安
Here is today's news.
首先是今日新聞
Morning.
早啊
Kaito, have you washed your face?
海斗，你洗臉了嗎？
Fine, I will.
好啦，我去洗
SHOPPING LIST
（購物清單）
Hey, there's no butter.
喂，奶油沒了
You could have bought some instead.
要吃就自己買啊
So scary!
好恐怖
Kii! You'll be late for school if you don't wake up now.
希衣，再不起床上學要遲到了
I don't want to go.
我不想去
Hurry up and get ready.
動作快一點
Oh, come on…
喂…
Yui!
小結！
You washed my uniform without softener again, didn't you?
妳又沒用柔軟精洗我的制服了 對不對？
It's so stiff that it's gross!
整件硬硬的好噁心
My socks aren't as white as before, too.
我的襪子也黃掉了
Learn how to use the washing machine yourself, then.
那你就自己學著用洗衣機啊
Seriously. And you call yourself the eldest child?
這樣妳還敢說自己是大姐？
Hey, Kakeru!
小翔！
Haven't I told you not to drink the milk directly from the box?
我不是說過 不要直接用盒子喝牛奶嗎？
Oh, right! I've been wanting to use the washroom the entire time.
對了，我一直想去廁所
Who's taking so long?
到底是誰用這麼久？
Dad! Just how long are you going to stay inside?
爸！你還要在裡面待多久？
I'm going to leak anytime!
我都要尿出來了
Oh, sorry! I'll be out in a moment.
抱歉…我馬上就出去
All right.
好
Sorry. Actually, there's something I want to tell everyone.
抱歉…
-Just how long were you going to take? -What?
-你到底上了多久？ -什麼？
I'll wait until you're done, then!
那我等你上完喔
Oh, Yui. It looks like we've run out of toilet paper.
小結，衛生紙好像用完了
When will you remember?
你到底什麼時候才會記得？
Didn't I tell you I placed some right here…
我不是說我放在這…
Seriously!
不會吧！
Oh, it's fine. I'll buy them on my way back from work.
沒關係啦，我下班再順便買回來
Mommy is going to help you wear your dress.
媽咪來幫你穿衣服
You'll really be late if you don't hurry, Kii.
希衣，妳再不快點真的要遲到了
How's school, Kaito?
海斗，學校怎麼樣啊？
Well, you're right.
說得也是
Breakfast time!
吃早餐囉…
Wait, Kakeru. Have you washed your hands?
等等，小翔，你洗手了沒？
How unhygienic. I can't believe you!
髒死了，不敢相信
Don't be so annoyed!
不要煩啦
Come on, now.
好了啦
Actually, there's something I want to tell everyone.
我其實有話跟大家說
-Eat properly, Kii. -Don't spill your food.
-希衣，好好吃飯 -別掉出來了
-Shut up! It didn't spill onto you. -It's dirty.
-閉嘴啦，又沒弄到你 -很髒耶
Everyone, will you listen to me?
大家，可以聽我說一下嗎？
Actually, today…
其實啊，今天…
Who's here this early?
誰會這麼早來？
I'll open the door!
我去開門！
Coming!
來了！
This is Suzuka Transport! We're here to deliver your items.
鈴鹿物流！我們將您的物品寄來了
Sorry, it's a little cluttered here.
抱歉，這裡有點亂
Come here, Kii. It's dangerous.
希衣，很危險，過來這邊
Let's go.
我們走
Please pardon us.
不好意思
Where should we put this?
這個要放哪裡？
Oh, on top of the dresser in the tatami room.
這個嘛，放在臥室的衣櫃上
We'll remove the packaging here, then.
那我們在這裡拆箱
Hey, what's that?
喂，那是什麼？
A Buddhist altar. Can't you see?
佛壇啊，你看不出來喔？
What's a Buddhist altar, Daddy?
爸爸，佛壇是什麼？
What? Well, that's…
什麼？那個是…
-Your signature and seal here, please. -Sure.
-請您在這裡簽名和蓋章 -好…
-Hey, what's a Buddhist altar? -What?
-佛壇是什麼？ -什麼？
From today onwards, imagine that Mommy is right in there.
從今天起，我們就想像媽咪住在裡面
-We'll pray to it every day. -Thank you!
-我們會每天拜拜 -謝謝！
Oh, thank you.
謝謝
But why? Mommy isn't in there!
為什麼？媽咪又不在裡面！
What? Like I said…
什麼？我剛說了…
Why would you buy something like that, Dad?
爸，你幹嘛買那種東西？
Well, your mom's 49th day is already over.
你們媽媽的49日已經結束了
-We can't wallow in sadness forever. -What's the "49th day"?
-我們不能一直難過下去 -什麼是“49日”？
What? Well…
什麼？這…
So… It's…
就是…
It is almost 7 a.m. now.
即將7點鐘了
We continue to strive to bring you the latest news.
我們繼續為您播報最新新聞
Let's eat.
吃早餐吧
Who is it this time?
這次又是誰？
I'll get the door!
我去開門！
Coming!
來了！
Kii!
希衣
I'm Mita, your housekeeper.
我是三田，您的家政婦
I am here on behalf of Harumi Housekeeping Agency.
我代表晴海家政婦介紹所來到這裡
What?
什麼？
May I enter?
我可以進去嗎？
Sure. Sorry, it's a little messy here.
當然，抱歉，這裡有點亂
Well, I thought they would have sent someone who looks the part.
我就在想他們會派人來負責家事
Oh, your slippers.
啊，拖鞋
-Don't worry. -What?
-沒關係 -什麼？
I have my own pair.
我有自備
Let's see. That's Yui, the eldest daughter.
這個嘛，這是長女小結
This is Kakeru, the eldest son. That's Kaito, my second son.
這是長男小翔，那是次男海斗
And this is Kii, the youngest.
還有老么希衣
I'm Mita, your housekeeper.
我是三田，您的家政婦
Hey. What's a housekeeper?
什麼是家政婦？
Well…
這個…
Starting today,
從今天起
Mita will be
三田會負責一整天的家事
and cooking our food for the entire day.
像是打掃家裡、洗衣服和煮飯
What?
什麼？
I didn't hear about this.
我不知道這件事
You knew, Yui?
姐，妳知道嗎？
Well, I guess.
大概吧
Why didn't you tell us such an important thing?
這麼重要的事妳怎麼沒說？
Sorry. That was my fault, Kakeru.
抱歉…小翔，這是我的錯
Isn't this fine?
這樣不好嗎？
We don't have someone who can do household chores here.
我們沒有人能做家事
Are you fine letting a stranger enter our house all of a sudden?
所以你能接受 突然讓一個陌生人進家裡嗎？
The service must be costly, too, right?
而且這樣很貴吧？
Don't worry, it will all work out.
別擔心，沒事的
Remember? We had money from your mom's insurance…
記得嗎？我們有媽媽的保險…
I mean, the 49th day is already over.
我是說，49日也結束了
Hey, so what's this "49th day"?
所以什麼是“49日”？
Well, that's…
啊，那個…
Well…
這個嘛…
Can someone explain it to her?
有人可以跟她解釋嗎？
The 49th day refers to the day when the deceased's soul,
49日也就是死者的靈魂
which was lingering in this world for 49 days,
會在這天離開人世
travels to the other world.
去到另一個世界
So you say your goodbyes and forget about that person.
所以你會和這個人道別，並忘了他
It's a day selfishly decided by the living.
這是自私的生者所訂定的日子
But Mommy is still here!
但媽咪還在這
Mommy is still right beside me!
媽咪還在我身邊
I'm sorry.
不好意思
They lost their mother suddenly,
他們突然失去媽媽
so they haven't really accepted it yet.
所以還沒辦法接受
She drowned in a nearby river.
她在附近的河流溺死了
So?
所以呢？
What?
什麼？
What should I start with, sir?
請問我要從什麼做起，主人？
Oh, for now…
啊，現在的話…
Either tidy up the house or do the laundry.
把家裡打掃一下或洗衣服
Just anything you feel necessary.
您覺得有必要的家事都可以
May I take a look around the house?
我可以四處看一下嗎？
Yes, of course.
當然可以
After I send Kii to school by 9 a.m.,
我9點送希衣去上學後
I will do the laundry and hang up the blankets to dry.
會洗衣服和晾被子
Looks like mold is growing in the bathroom and washroom,
浴室和廁所似乎長黴了
so I will clean it up.
我會打掃乾淨
Softener, toilet paper.
柔軟精、衛生紙
Butter.
奶油
Shampoo, garbage bags…
洗髮精、垃圾袋…
You do not have those.
這些都沒了
I will buy them when I'm out grocery shopping.
會在採買時順便買回來
I will change the light bulb here.
我會把這裡的燈泡換掉
How should I tidy up the children's rooms?
我該怎麼打掃孩子們的房間？
What?
什麼？
Well…
這個嘛…
For now, I will try to tidy up the rooms without making any changes
總之，我盡量在不改變擺設的情況下
as much as possible.
清理乾淨
Is that all right?
這樣可以嗎？
Yes.
可以
Understood.
我知道了
I will water and fertilize the potted plants.
我會替盆栽澆水和施肥
The windows seem dirty,
窗戶看起來很髒
so I will wipe them clean.
我會擦拭乾淨
What would you like to have for dinner?
你們晚餐想吃什麼？
Oh, well…
這個…
One last thing.
最後一件事
Yes?
是的？
What should I do with that room?
那間房間該怎麼處理？
Right…
也是
I did think about cleaning up the room eventually…
我確實也想找時間清理…
You don't have to clean that room!
那間房間不用打掃
Then, are you planning to just leave the things there?
那你是打算留著那些東西嗎？
-You want them thrown away? -I didn't say that!
-你是想丟掉嗎？ -我沒這麼說！
-Stop it. -What do you think, Yui?
-別吵了 -那姐妳是怎麼想的？
What?
什麼？
Could you leave the room as it is for now?
總之，那間房間可以先別動嗎？
As you wish.
明白了
I will begin my work now.
我現在就開始工作
Yui has to take the 7:52 a.m. bus.
小結要搭7點52分的公車
Kakeru and Kaito will be late
小翔和海斗如果沒在8點前出門
if they do not leave by 8 a.m.,
就會遲到 所以你們兩個要準備出門了
I suggest you leave earlier than usual, Mr. Asuda.
阿須田先生，我建議你今天提早出門
It was reported in the news
新聞報導說
that the traffic will be congested today.
今天路上會塞車
Oh, okay.
好的
-Oh, no! -Yikes!
-糟了！ -糟糕！
-Hurry up! -I know!
-快一點！ -我知道啦！
Oh, no!
完蛋了
Have a safe trip.
路上小心
Mita. Here is the house key, and the grocery allowance for now.
三田小姐，這是家裡的鑰匙 還有購物金
-Mr. Asuda. -Yes?
-主人 -怎麼了？
Your necktie is crooked.
您的領帶鬆了
Good morning.
早安
This is Ms. Minagawa, our neighbor.
這位是鄰居皆川太太
Well, this is…
這位是…
I'm Mita, the housekeeper.
我是家政婦三田
Yui! Got a minute?
小結！妳有空嗎？
I told you not to talk to me in school.
我說過在學校別跟我說話
People would misunderstand if they know I'm related to a teacher.
要是大家知道我跟老師有親戚關係 會產生誤會的
Sorry. Anyway, I want to go cook at your house today.
抱歉，總之，我今天會去妳家煮飯
Tell me what you ate yesterday.
快告訴我你們昨天吃什麼
You wouldn't want the same thing--
我才不會煮一樣的…
-We're fine. -What?
-我們沒事 -什麼？
We have a housekeeper starting today.
從今天起，我們有家政婦
No way! I didn't hear about that!
騙人的吧，我怎麼不知道？
Why did Keiichi do that?
姐夫幹嘛請家政婦？
I could help with the household chores!
家事我可以幫忙啊
In any case, the matter is settled.
總之，事情就是這樣
You don't have to come over. Don't you dare!
請妳絕對不要過來！
we decided on curved paths to control the driving speed.
我們決定用彎道來控制車速
And by hiding the utility poles underneath,
而且將電纜地下化的話
we were able to create a beautiful town landscape.
就可以創造美麗的街道景觀
These are the landscape planning key points
以上就是上次會議
we discussed in our last meeting.
討論的街景規劃重點
Do you have anything to add, Chief?
課長，您還有想補充的嗎？
What?
什麼？
Right…
對了…
As the person in charge of this important project,
身為這個重要計劃的負責人
I'm glad to have reliable subordinates like all of you.
我很開心有你們這麼優秀的部下
There you go again. You're so good at flattery, Chief.
又來了…課長嘴巴真甜
-Give me a minute. -Okay.
-等我一下 -好
Kazama.
風間
What is it?
什麼事？
Well…
這個…
I…
我…
How should I say this?
該怎麼說呢？
Hey! Wait!
嘿，等等
Oh, hello? Sorry to call while you're busy.
喂？抱歉打擾您
I am Harumi from Harumi Housekeeping Agency.
我是晴海家政婦介紹所的晴海
Oh, hello.
是，妳好
So what is the matter?
有什麼事嗎？
to your house today.
應該已經去到您府上了
So I was wondering if you're thinking about that.
我在想，您有沒有考慮“那個”
What? What do you mean?
什麼？哪個？
Well, it's nothing too serious.
其實也沒什麼大不了的
Depending on the situation,
只是就一般情況而言
we do have
我們確實有不少的客戶
requesting to have the housekeeper changed.
都提出要更換家政婦
I see…
原來如此…
I was a little surprised since she didn't look like a housekeeper,
我是有點驚訝，她看起來不像家政婦
but she's pretty and she doesn't say much.
但她很漂亮，也不多話
Exactly.
沒錯
That lady doesn't really smile,
她完全不笑
and she never says anything else other than what's necessary.
非必要也不會開口說話
I see.
我知道了
Is that so?
原來是這樣啊？
But…
不過呢
she is definitely top-notch when it comes to her work.
她在工作上確實沒話說
She'll get all the basic things done perfectly!
能將所有基本的事情做到完美
I see. I have to go now.
我了解了，我先掛電話了
Wait, one more thing!
等等，還有一件事
What is it?
什麼事？
She will do anything you ask.
您叫她做什麼，她都會做
Could you please be careful with that?
這方面可以請您小心點嗎？
Excuse me, but may I know what the problem with that is?
抱歉，但這樣會有什麼問題嗎？
To put it in extreme terms…
極端一點來說
If you tell her to kill someone…
如果您叫她殺人
She will really do it.
她真的會做喔
What?
什麼？
Don't worry about it!
別擔心啦
I mean,
我的意思是
you don't seem like the type who would tell her to do that!
您看起來也不像會叫她去殺人的人
Please excuse me!
先這樣啦
Okay.
好
I'm home!
我回來了
Welcome home.
歡迎回家
Hey…
嘿…
I'm home.
我回來了
Shall I help you get undressed?
要幫您脫衣服嗎？
What?
什麼？
No, you don't have to do that!
不用了，妳不必這樣做
Oh, sorry. I wanted to get some water.
不好意思，我想喝點水
If you tell her to kill someone…
“如果您叫她殺人
She will really do it.
她真的會做喔”
I'm sorry, but could you please not stand behind me?
抱歉，可以請您不要站在我身後嗎？
What?
什麼？
It's just that the house looks too different, so I was surprised.
只是家裡看起來很不一樣 所以我很驚訝
-Daddy! -What is it?
-爸爸… -怎麼了？
The washroom and bathroom are sparkling clean!
浴室和廁所都亮晶晶喔
Really?
真的嗎？
You're right.
真的耶
It smells good, too.
好香啊
What's wrong, Yui?
怎麼了，小結？
There's a cockroach!
有蟑螂
-What? Where? -It's running around!
-什麼？哪裡？ -牠跑來跑去！
-Where is it? -Hey! What are you guys doing?
-在哪裡… -嘿！你們在幹嘛？
What's up? It's time to study--
怎麼了？我在讀書…
There it is!
在那裡
Dinner is ready.
晚餐準備好了
They look delicious.
看起來好好吃啊
Excuse me. Was the money enough?
不好意思，錢夠用嗎？
Don't worry. Here is the receipt.
不用擔心，收據在這裡
Right…
好的
Thank you very much.
非常感謝妳
Well then, shall we eat?
那大家要開動了嗎？
-Thank you for the food.
我開動了
So good!
好好吃
We haven't had any proper food for two months, after all.
我們兩個月沒吃到正常的食物了耶
-Shut up. -But still,
-吵死了 -但是
this is a little bland compared to our usual.
口味稍微比平常淡
Just now you were so happy that your uniform feels fluffy.
你剛剛才因為制服很柔軟很開心
Shut up! You should stop studying when it's time to eat!
閉嘴啦！你才是，吃飯別念書
-I agree, Kaito. -But I couldn't solve this question.
-我同意，海斗 -但我這題解不出來
Right. Do you know the answer, Dad?
對了，爸，你知道答案嗎？
It's a question set for the middle school that I'm applying for.
這是我要申請的國中出的考題
Let's see.
我看看
Want to answer it, Yui?
小結，不然妳來解解看？
Don't throw it to me.
別丟給我
So no one knows the answer?
沒人知道答案嗎？
7y over 3 plus two.
2減7y再除以3
Oh, wow. She's right.
好厲害，答對了
Mita also remembers all the names of AKB48!
三田小姐也記得AKB48的所有成員喔
No way! Say it.
騙人，妳說說看
Atsuko Maeda, Yuko Oshima, Yuki Kashiwagi,
前田敦子、大島優子、柏木由紀
Mariko Shinoda, Mayu Watanabe,
篠田麻里子、渡邊麻友
-I'll get it! -Haruna Kojima, Minami Takahashi,
-我去開門 -小嶋陽菜、高橋南
-Tomomi Itano… -You can stop now, Mita.
-板野友美… -三田小姐，不用唸了
-Who's here this late? -Don't tell me…
-這個時間會是誰啊？ -不會是…
Sorry that I'm late, everyone!
抱歉大家，我來晚了
I was buying groceries at the supermarket,
我在超市買東西時
and I left my wallet back in school…
才發現錢包放在學校…
Well…
這個…
You don't need to worry about our dinner, Urara.
小麗，晚餐妳不用操心
Seems like it.
好像是呢
Right.
對了
This is Mita. She will be with us starting today.
她是三田，從今天起來我們家
Mita.
三田小姐
This is Urara,
她是小麗，我老婆的妹妹
I'm Mita, the housekeeper.
我是家政婦三田
Hello, I'm Urara Yuki.
妳好，我是結誠麗
I'm 12 years younger than my sister,
我比姐姐小12歲
so we don't really seem like sisters.
所以我們看起來不像姐妹
I teach PE in Yui's school.
我在小結的學校當體育老師
Excuse me…
不好意思
It will be a waste to throw these, so please use them.
這些丟掉也可惜，就給妳用吧
I understand.
我知道了
Hey…
嘿…
Why don't you join us, Urara?
小麗，妳要一起吃嗎？
What? Really…
什麼？真的…
-Also, there are things to do at home. -I see.
-而且我家還有事 -我知道了
And…
那…
You don't have to see me off. Continue your dinner!
不用送我，你們繼續吃
It's fine! See you!
就這樣，再見
I'm glad she went back immediately.
還好她很快就走了
Things always get messy when Urara comes.
小麗只要來，就會搞得一團亂
Isn't that going overboard?
這樣講會不會太過分了？
Everyone! Sorry, but I forgot something important!
抱歉大家，我忘記一件很重要的事
Kii's birthday is in two days, right?
希衣後天生日，對吧？
Why don't we all celebrate together?
我們要不要一起慶祝？
It's fine, but…
是不錯，但…
We're not really in the mood for it.
我們還沒有那個心情
Also, there's no one organizing it this year…
而且今年也沒人準備…
Don't say that. Let's have a party together!
別這麼說，我們來辦派對吧
Who was the one who couldn't make it to the party because of work last year?
是誰去年工作到太晚 所以來不及回來？
I'll come home early for sure this year.
我今年一定會早點回家
Right. Is there any birthday present you want, Kii?
對了，希衣，妳想要什麼生日禮物？
Just say anything you want.
什麼都可以喔
-Really? -Yes. Just say it.
-真的嗎？ -對，妳說吧
Mommy!
媽咪
What?
什麼？
I… I want Mommy. I want Mommy to be here!
我…我要媽咪，我想媽咪了
Well, that's a little…
但這個有點…
Don't say strange things, Kii.
希衣，不要提奇怪的要求
What about a panda stuffed toy? Didn't you want that?
熊貓玩偶怎麼樣？妳不想要嗎？
No. I want Mommy!
不要，我要媽咪
Don't act like a baby.
別像個小嬰兒一樣…
No! I want Mommy.
不，我要媽咪
I want to see Mommy!
我想見媽咪
Don't cry, Kii!
別哭了，希衣
Man.
天啊
It's all because someone mentioned having a birthday party.
都是某人提到生日派對的關係
Oh, I get it!
我知道了
Kii! I'll let you meet Mommy.
希衣，我會讓妳和媽咪見面
Really?
真的嗎？
Yes! So look forward to your birthday.
對，所以好好期待生日吧
-Thanks, Urara! -Count on me!
-小麗，謝謝妳 -包在我身上
Urara said she'll let me meet Mommy!
小麗說會讓我見到媽咪
Urara. Are you sure it's fine to make that promise?
小麗，做出那樣的承諾沒問題嗎？
Well…
這個…
It will all be fine! Just leave it to me!
沒問題的…一切都包在我身上
Bye! See you. I'll come visit again!
先這樣，我到時候再過來
This is definitely not going to end well.
怎麼可能沒問題啊？
I have a bad feeling about this.
我有不好的預感
Things really get messy when Urara is around.
只要小麗在，事情都會一團亂
What now, Dad?
爸，該怎麼辦？
What?
什麼？
Oh… Okay.
這個嘛…
Mr. Asuda. I will leave the house now if there is nothing else.
主人，如果沒別的事，我就離開了
Sure.
好
Good work today.
辛苦妳了
Excuse me, Mita.
三田小姐，不好意思
It's about Urara.
關於小麗
What do you think I should do?
妳覺得我該怎麼做？
What do you mean by that?
您的意思是什麼？
I mean…
我是覺得…
She's bright and she tries her best in everything.
她很陽光，也很認真做事
I'm grateful that she's been with us ever since my wife passed away.
我很感激她在我老婆過世後 陪著我們
But whenever she tries to do something to help us,
但只要她想幫點什麼忙
things always tend to backfire instead.
最後總是會造成反效果
It's pretty troublesome.
這真的很困擾
Oh, for example…
舉例來說…
She invited the kids out for a drive to cheer them up,
她帶孩子去兜風，想讓他們心情變好
but she got a flat tire in the middle of a mountain.
但車子卻在山裡爆胎了
When Urara tried to pitch a tent at a campsite,
她想在營區搭帳篷時
tons of bugs and insects appeared all of a sudden.
卻突然出現一大堆蟲子
Well…
那個…
What I mean is…
我的意思是
I'm really sorry to ask you for this favor,
雖然這個要求有點不合理
but could you ask her
但可以請妳幫我問她
Well, you see…
妳想想
It will be really bad
要是希衣受傷之類的
if Kii gets injured or something.
就不好了
This is Urara's address.
這是小麗的地址
I mean, I know that I should be the one making the trip.
我當然知道我應該要自己去
But I just don't get along with her father.
但我跟岳父就是處不好
Even if I were really there,
就算我去到她家
he would just say things like, "I don't even want to see your face!"
岳父也只會說 “我不想再看到你的臉”之類的話
Is this an order?
這是命令嗎？
What?
什麼？
Well, yes.
對
Understood.
我了解了
YUKI RESIDENCE
（結城家）
What do you want this early in the morning?
這麼早是要幹什麼？
Who are you?
妳是誰？
I'm Mita, a housekeeper.
我是家政婦三田
CERTIFICATE OF COMMENDATION
（獎狀）
So you're the housekeeper Urara mentioned?
所以妳就是小麗提到的家政婦？
Yes.
是的
So? What do you want?
然後呢？妳想幹嘛？
Mr. Asuda ordered me to check
阿須田先生叫我來
what Ms. Urara's plans are.
確認麗小姐打算做什麼
What do you mean?
妳這是什麼意思？
Explain yourself clearly.
把話說清楚
Yesterday,
昨天，麗小姐來到家裡
and suggested to hold a birthday party for Kii.
提議要替希衣辦生日派對
Kii was asked what birthday present she would like,
希衣被問到生日禮物想要什麼
and she replied, "I want to see Mommy."
她回答“我想要見媽咪”
Everyone was extremely troubled.
大家都很為難
But Ms. Urara promised to let Kii see her mother.
但麗小姐答應要讓希衣見到媽媽
Kii believed her words and is looking forward to her birthday.
希衣相信了，很期待生日的到來
Mr. Asuda is worried,
阿須田先生很擔心
and he would like to know what Ms. Urara has in mind.
他想知道麗小姐打算做什麼
But he is bad at dealing with you.
但他說他很不會跟您溝通
If he had come, he said you would shout at him,
他說如果他來了，您會對他大吼
"I don't even want to see your face!"
“我不想再看到你的臉”
So he asked me to make the trip over.
所以他請我來一趟
What was that?
什麼意思啊？
Hey, Urara!
喂，麗！
Urara! Come over!
麗，過來一下
I've had enough of that man!
我受夠那個男人了
He should come over himself if he has something to ask!
他想問什麼應該要自己來
That coward!
真是個懦夫
If only Nagiko hadn't been deceived by that man
要不是止子被那個男人騙了
and had a shotgun marriage with him,
還奉子成婚
she wouldn't have drowned herself in the river!
她也不會跳河自盡
What, Dad? I have to leave soon. I won't make it in time!
爸，幹嘛？ 我馬上就要出門了，快遲到了
Pardon my intrusion.
不好意思打擾了
Urara. Just what did you do?
麗，妳做了什麼好事？
How could you promise to let a kid meet someone who died?
妳怎麼能答應要讓孩子見死掉的人？
Shut up. Could you not scold me like you did when you were a principal?
吵死了，你可以 別再像個校長一樣訓話嗎？
You don't seem to know your responsibility as a teacher!
妳似乎不曉得身為老師的職責
How could you make an empty promise to a child?
妳怎麼能對小孩開空頭支票？
That's the last thing you should do as a teacher!
身為老師，妳不應該這麼做！
Also,
還有
I told you to never visit that home again!
我不是叫妳不准再去那個家了嗎？
I'm free to do that!
這是我的自由
Why don't you show more love for your grandchildren?
你為什麼不多關心孫子和孫女？
You always frown and lecture them. No wonder they dislike you!
你總是嚴肅地訓話 難怪他們都討厭你
You could also stop being so prejudiced against Keiichi and be more accepting!
你不該對姐夫有這麼多成見 你要多接納他一點啊
Shut up!
吵死了
No matter what,
不管怎樣
I will never forgive that man!
我絕不會原諒那個男人
Like I said, stop getting angry!
就說了，別這樣兇我
I'm not getting angry at you!
我不是在兇妳
Jeez! He always runs away when things don't look good for him!
天啊，只要不順他的意，他就會跑走
Sorry that you had to see that.
抱歉讓妳看到這一幕
What?
什麼？
You told him everything?
妳全都告訴他了嗎？
Yes.
是的
So…
那…
What did he say?
爸說什麼？
"He should come over himself if he has something to ask!"
“他想問什麼應該要自己來
"That coward!"
真是個懦夫”
That was what he said.
他是這麼說的
I see.
是嗎？
So… What did Urara say?
那…小麗怎麼說？
"I came up with a great idea which will let Kii meet with her mother,
“我想到一個很棒的點子 能讓希衣見到媽媽
so don't worry!"
所以請放心”
That was what she said.
她是這麼說的
What is that idea she came up with?
她想出什麼點子？
Apparently, she's keeping it a secret until the day itself.
顯然她想要保密，當天再公布
It is almost time to pick Kii up, so may I end the call here?
我差不多要去接希衣了 可以先這樣嗎？
Yes. I understand.
好，我了解了
MISAWA KINDERGARTEN
（三澤幼稚園）
It hurts…
好痛…
At this rate, I can't let my child attend this kindergarten safely.
這樣下去，我不可能放心讓小孩 繼續待在這間幼稚園
I am really sorry!
真的非常抱歉
Excuse me, do you have a minute?
不好意思，您有時間嗎？
What is it?
什麼事？
Kii made Tsubasa cry.
希衣把小翼弄哭了
She told him that she's meeting her mother on her birthday,
她跟小翼說，她生日時會見到媽媽
and Tsubasa told her
然後小翼告訴她
that she can't meet her mother since she died.
她媽媽已經死了，不可能見面
You…
妳是…
You're the housekeeper at the Asuda residence, right?
阿須田家的家政婦，對吧？
Just how does he raise his kids?
他到底是怎麼教小孩的？
She was so mean to Tsubasa.
她對我們家的小翼很惡劣
There's no point discussing this with you,
跟妳說也沒用
so could you tell her father to come to our house and apologize?
可以請妳跟她爸說 叫他來我們家道歉嗎？
Understood.
我了解了
Let's head home, Tsubasa.
小翼，我們回家吧
Let's go home.
我們回家吧
Can we hold hands?
我們可以牽手嗎？
Yes.
好的
Why are your hands so cold?
妳的手怎麼這麼冰？
I'm sorry.
抱歉
Hey.
那個
Is it true that I can meet Mommy if I die?
如果我死掉 是不是就可以見到媽咪？
Tsubasa told me that.
小翼跟我說
"Your mommy is in heaven,
“妳的媽咪在天國
so you have to die if you want to meet her."
妳想見她的話，就要死掉才行”
Some people believe in that.
有些人這麼相信
Then…
那麼…
Could we both go together?
我們可以一起去嗎？
Let's meet Mommy.
我們去找媽咪
As you wish.
我知道了
Hey, what are you two doing?
喂，妳們在幹嘛？
Hey, hold up!
喂，等等！
Hey!
喂！
What were you planning to do with my little sister?
妳想對我妹做什麼？
Kii! Are you all right, Kii?
希衣，妳有沒有怎麼樣？
Hey, Kaito! That housekeeper is bad news!
喂，海斗，那個家政婦很糟糕耶
She was definitely trying to die!
她絕對是想死
And that was where Mom drowned, too!
而且那裡還是媽媽溺死的地方
Weren't you just imagining it?
你是不是想太多了？
He's right.
對啊
Didn't Kii also say she was just picking up stones?
希衣不也說她只是想撿石頭嗎？
What are you saying?
妳在說什麼啊？
You're the eldest, so why don't you show more concern for your sister?
妳是大姐，不該多關心一下妹妹嗎？
And you're just a kid, so could you stop boasting that you're the eldest son?
那既然你只是個小孩 可以別再以長男自居嗎？
Then what should we do? Kii's birthday is tomorrow!
那怎麼辦啊？ 明天就是希衣的生日了耶
I wonder how Urara will mess things up this time.
我在想這次小麗會惹出什麼麻煩
It will be fine.
沒事的啦
Not even Urara is capable of summoning Mom's spirit.
小麗是沒辦法把媽媽帶回來的
I'm sure even Kii understands
我想希衣一定也知道
that it's not possible to see Mom.
不可能會見到媽媽的
INBOX TAKUYA OZAWA
（收件匣，小澤拓也）
What? Was that your boyfriend?
誰啊？男朋友嗎？
What? No way, seriously?
什麼？真的假的啊？
Don't look at my phone.
不要看我的手機啦
Hey! Our conversation isn't over yet.
喂！我們還沒討論完耶
If you're that worried, why don't you tell Dad about it?
要是你那麼擔心，幹嘛不跟爸說？
I brought you your washed clothes.
這是您洗好的衣物
Right…
好
Thank you very much.
非常感謝妳
Mita.
三田小姐
Excuse me…
那個…
What do you think I should do?
妳覺得我該怎麼做？
About the birthday party tomorrow.
關於明天的生日派對
That is…
那是…
something you should decide for yourself.
您要自己決定的事情
MOM: I'M SORRY, YUI.
（媽媽：小結，我很抱歉）
EISEI ACADEMY HIGH SCHOOL
（英成學園高等學校）
PHOTOGRAPHY CLUB
（攝影社）
Hey. What are you doing?
喂，妳在幹嘛？
Oh, it's nothing.
沒幹嘛
Those guys left the camera here again.
那些傢伙又把相機留在這了
You know…
對了
Shall we go somewhere today if you're free?
如果妳有空的話 等等要不要出去逛逛？
-What? -Well…
-什麼？ -那個…
We haven't had a good talk ever since your mom passed away.
自從妳媽去世後 我們都沒好好講過話
Right…
這個嘛…
-I'm sorry. -No, I wasn't trying to blame you.
-對不起 -不…我不是在怪妳
Besides, it's hard for us to be alone in school.
而且，在學校我們也很難獨處
You're right.
也是
Who is it?
誰呀？
It's my younger brother.
我弟
Please excuse me!
不好意思
Hello?
喂？
Where are you now, Yui?
姐，妳在哪裡？
I'm still in school. What is it?
我還在學校呀，怎麼了？
Things are getting really bad here!
大事不妙了啊
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
It's a mess all because of Urara!
小麗搞砸了
Just come home quickly!
快點回來就是了
Hey! Hello?
等等，喂？
Excuse me…
那個…
What are you doing, Mita?
三田小姐，妳在做什麼？
I was told that I do not need to prepare dinner today.
我被告知今天不用準備晚餐
Did Urara tell you that?
該不會是小麗吧？
Yes.
是的
What? What's going on?
咦？這是怎樣？
Urara?
小麗？
Welcome home! Dinner will be done in a while.
歡迎回家，晚餐馬上就好了
Jeez, that hurt!
啊，痛死了
Hey, what's going on?
喂，這是怎樣？
and she is preparing the same food!
說要準備一樣的食物
She thinks doing that will make Kii happy since it will just be like seeing Mom!
她覺得希衣會很高興 因為就好像媽媽還在一樣
On top of that, she's wearing the same clothing Mom wore last year.
而且，她還跟媽媽去年穿得一樣
She was wearing the same apron as Mom.
連圍裙也一樣
I just can't believe her.
真是不敢置信
Wait, where's Dad?
等等，爸呢？
Pretty sure he's going to be home late again.
他一定又會晚回家了
Here, it's all done!
大功告成
Come sit down, everyone!
大家快坐好
Sorry to keep you waiting, Kii! Let's eat.
希衣，抱歉讓妳等這麼久，來吃吧
Come on. Sit down, everyone.
來吧，大家都坐下吧
Your father is running late, so we should start first.
你們的爸爸會晚回來，我們先吃
What do you want to eat, Kii?
希衣，妳想吃哪個？
How about some salad? Here you go.
沙拉怎麼樣？來
-I don't want any. -What? Why?
-我不要 -咦？為什麼？
-Here you go. -Kii dislikes cherry tomatoes.
-給妳 -希衣討厭小番茄
Really? I'm sorry. But look…
真的嗎？抱歉，但妳看…
Your mom made these last year.
妳媽去年也做沙拉耶
Then…
那…
Have some fried chicken.
吃點炸雞吧
I'm sure it will taste just like your mom's.
我保證吃起來跟媽媽煮的一樣
These aren't Mom's cooking at all!
這才不是媽媽做的料理
Kii. Apologize to Urara.
希衣，跟小麗說對不起
It's fine!
沒關係…
Then, shall we order takeout?
不然，我們點外送？
What do you want? Pizza, or maybe sushi?
妳想吃什麼？披薩還是壽司？
I don't care.
我不在乎
I want to see Mommy!
我想見媽咪
Let me meet Mommy!
讓我見媽咪
Right,
好
so you can think of me as your mommy!
那妳可以把我當成媽咪
You're not Mommy, Urara!
妳才不是媽咪，小麗
Don't sit here!
妳不可以坐在這
This is Mommy's seat!
這是媽咪的位子
Sorry. Actually…
抱歉…
Sorry.
抱歉
Seriously, what are you doing?
妳到底在搞什麼啊？
I'll clean it up.
我會清理乾淨
I'm sorry.
不好意思
-Come on, Kii. -Let's go, Kaito.
-起來吧，希衣 -海斗，走吧
Kii.
希衣
I'm home.
我回來了
Sorry, I just couldn't leave work early…
對不起，我沒辦法早點離開公司
What?
咦？
What happened?
發生什麼事了？
-I'm sorry, Keiichi. -What?
-抱歉，姐夫 -什麼？
It's all my fault.
都是我的錯
I'll go home.
我先走了
Wait, what?
等等，什麼？
Urara? Wait…
小麗？等等…
What's the matter, Kii?
希衣，怎麼了呀？
Come on, cheer up.
別哭了嘛
That's right.
對了
I got you a present!
我買了禮物要給妳
Here you go.
妳看
It's the panda stuffed toy that you wanted!
這是妳想要的熊貓玩偶
-See? -Wow, awesome!
-妳看 -哇，好棒喔！
Aren't you happy, Kii?
希衣，好棒喔
I wanted this, too!
我也好想要耶
I don't need things like this!
我才不想要這個
You better stop it, Kii.
妳不要胡鬧囉，希衣
I won't.
我不要
I want to see Mommy!
我想要見媽咪
Mommy!
媽咪
I want to see Mom, too!
我也想見媽啊
But…
但是…
She died.
她過世了
She's no longer with us.
不會回來了
Tomorrow, the day after, or even the day after that…
明天、後天或大後天
We can't see Mom again!
我們都再也看不到媽媽了！
No matter how much you want to see her,
不管妳多想見她
it's impossible!
都永遠見不到了！
Yui.
姐
You didn't have to take it that far…
妳也不用說成這樣…
Then, why don't you let her meet Mom?
那不然你帶她去見媽媽，好不好？
It's all because we leave her things lying around here.
這都是因為到處都是媽媽的東西
Mita.
三田小姐
Will you throw all her things away?
妳可以把這些東西都扔掉嗎？
As you wish.
我知道了
Wait. Mita…
三田小姐，等等
Hey…
喂
What are you doing? You've got to be kidding me!
妳在幹什麼？妳開什麼玩笑？
Stop it already!
快住手
Just throw all of them away.
全部都丟掉
-Stop it! -Burn all of them!
-住手！ -全部都燒掉！
Why don't you say something, Dad?
爸，你為什麼不說點什麼？
What? Well…
什麼？這個…
You also think we're better off doing this, right?
爸也覺得這樣做比較好，不是嗎？
That's not what I think…
我沒這麼想…
Yui?
小結？
Even if we keep them,
就算留下這些東西
Mom will never come back to life!
媽也永遠不會活過來！
-Yui! -Move!
-姐！ -走開！
We don't need this, nor this!
這些都不需要了
I used to think that…
我以前覺得…
I'm a good older sister.
我是個很稱職的大姐
But…
但是…
I realized something after Mom died.
媽媽死後我才發現
In reality…
事實上…
I couldn't do anything an elder sister can do.
身為大姐該做的事，我全都做不到
Not cooking, not doing the laundry.
我不會煮飯，不會洗衣服
Not tidying, nor even taking care of siblings.
不會整理家裡，甚至不會照顧弟妹
I couldn't do them at all!
我什麼都不會
I have to get myself together.
我應該要振作起來
I know I have to do my best!
我知道我要加油
But it's just impossible for me!
但我就是做不到
I don't even feel like taking photos, which I used to love!
就連我以前喜歡的攝影
Hey, what are you doing?
喂，妳在幹嘛啊？
Damn you, stop that right now!
該死，妳給我住手
Why are you doing this?
妳在做什麼？
Why?
為什麼要這麼做？
-Damn it! -Hey!
-該死！ -喂！
-Why? -Kakeru!
-為什麼… -小翔，住手
Are you guys fine with Mom's belongings being gone?
你們難道要眼睜睜 看著媽的東西被燒掉嗎？
Kakeru!
小翔！
Then burn that thing too!
那就把那個東西也燒掉！
I'm the worst.
我是最糟糕的
You know…
你們知道…
When I try to remember Mom…
當我試著回想起媽…
I only remember her nagging and reprimanding me…
我只記得她唸我或是罰我的時候
and me saying things like, "You're annoying!"
而我只會說“吵死了！”
Or "Just leave me alone already!"
或是“不要煩我行不行！”
I should have been nicer to her.
我應該要對她好一點的
I should have thanked her.
我應該要感謝她，感謝有她在旁邊
I should have told her, "I'm sorry I was mean."
我應該要跟她說 “對不起我態度這麼糟”
I should have apologized to her!
我應該要跟她道歉的
What the hell should I do now?
我現在到底該怎麼做？
What's with this turn of events?
現在是怎麼樣？
Everyone is here crying.
每個人都在哭
Aren't you sad?
你難道不難過嗎？
You…
你…
You still call yourself Mom's kid?
你這樣還算是媽的兒子嗎？
Of course, I want to cry, too!
我當然也很想哭啊！
But…
但是…
What am I supposed to do when she died all of a sudden?
媽突然就過世了，我該怎麼辦？
Even if I tried my best and entered a private school,
即使我努力考進了私立學校
she's not here anymore to praise me!
媽再也不會在身邊誇獎我了！
I wanted to have Mom all to myself.
我想跟媽分享所有事
I wanted to tell her all about my future and my dreams!
我想跟她說我未來想幹嘛 有什麼夢想！
But I can't do it anymore!
但我再也沒辦法了
I have no idea what Mom was thinking!
我搞不懂媽到底在想什麼
Why did she go off and die on her own?
她為什麼突然就過世了？
What did she think of me?
她到底對我的想法是什麼？
Mom!
媽！
It's my fault.
都是我的錯
Mommy died because of me!
媽咪會死，都是因為我
What are you talking about, Kii?
希衣，妳在說什麼？
I hate tomatoes.
我討厭吃番茄
Mom was angry and told me to eat it.
媽媽很生氣，叫我要吃
And I told her,
然後我就說
"I hope you die, Mommy!"
“媽咪，我希望妳死掉！”
Then, Mommy really died.
然後媽咪就真的死掉了
I'm sorry, Mommy!
媽咪，對不起
I'm sorry!
對不起
Kii…
希衣…
Is that why you wanted to meet Mom?
妳就是因為這樣才想見媽媽嗎？
It's not your fault, Kii.
希衣，這不是妳的錯
You know that Mommy loves you, Kii.
妳知道媽咪很愛妳
Daddy…
爸爸…
Hey!
喂！
What are you guys doing?
你們在幹什麼？
What will you do if our house catches fire?
要是害我們家失火怎麼辦？
Please put out the fire, Mita.
三田小姐，請把火撲滅
As you wish.
我知道了
I understand things are tough since your lost your wife,
我知道你失去太太很難過
but isn't this ridiculous?
但這樣會不會太扯啊？
No wonder Kii would hit other kids in school.
難怪希衣在學校會打人
I'm sorry.
我很抱歉
If you don't educate Kii properly, she's going to be led astray.
要是你不好好教育 希衣一定會變壞的
What will you do if she causes more problems?
如果她又惹出什麼麻煩 你打算怎麼辦？
Without a mother in the household,
一個家要是沒有媽媽
your family is hardly normal anymore--
家庭就很難維持正常
Stop!
住手
I just didn't want your house to be caught on fire.
我只是不想害你們家失火
Ms. Minagawa…
阿姨
Your makeup is totally melting.
妳的妝都花掉了
I won't take this lying down.
我不會這樣就算了
I'll bring this up at the next neighborhood council meeting.
我一定會在下次社區會議上說出來
What's this?
這是什麼？
It's hot!
好燙！
Are you all right?
沒事吧？
Wait, Mita…
三田小姐，等等
Hey, isn't it hot?
喂，妳不怕燙嗎？
What are these?
這是什麼？
Your mom was really proud of these.
你們的媽媽很喜歡這個
She said she went to the river with Kii,
她說她跟希衣一起去河邊
and received these beautiful stones.
希衣把這些漂亮的石頭送給她
It's the first present she received from Kii,
這是希衣送的第一份禮物
so she said she'll treasure it forever.
所以她說會珍藏一輩子
Didn't I tell you?
我沒說過嗎？
Mommy…
媽咪呀
Mommy loves you, Kii.
很愛妳唷，希衣
Yes!
太棒了！
All right!
好了
Let's have the birthday party!
我們來辦生日派對吧
Just like how we did when Mom was still around.
就像媽媽還在時一樣
But what about all the food?
但是食物怎麼辦？
Oh, right.
對耶…
Mita.
三田小姐
Could you whip up something?
妳能夠做點料理嗎？
Sure.
可以
All right.
太好了
Oh, what about a cake?
那蛋糕怎麼辦？
We have one. Ms. Urara brought one.
有一個蛋糕，麗小姐帶來的
This is awesome.
好漂亮喔
Urara forgot about the candles.
小麗忘記拿蠟燭了
Mita. I don't suppose you have candles, do you?
三田小姐，妳該不會有蠟燭吧？
I do.
有的
Exactly six of them, too.
剛好六根耶
All right, I'll light them up.
太棒了，我來點吧
Okay.
好了
You always sing it, Kakeru.
-快樂 -小翔，都是你在唱耶
I couldn't help it! Mom always made me sing it.
我忍不住嘛，媽每次都會逼我唱
Dad and you guys should join me! Come on!
大家一起唱嘛，快點
Three, go!
來，唱！
I'm out of sync.
-我走音了
-Happy birthday! -Happy birthday, Kii!
-生日快樂… -生日快樂，希衣！
Isn't Kaito supposed to give her the card next?
接下來是不是海斗要送卡片？
I didn't prepare one. I only made them because Mom made me.
我沒準備耶，每次都是媽叫我準備的
Mita. What about a card…
三田小姐，卡片的話…
I have one.
有的
Here you go.
給你
Weren't you supposed to give the presents, Yui?
姐，妳是不是該送禮物？
Oh, sorry. I didn't prepare one this year.
啊，對不起，我今年沒準備
Give me a moment.
啊，等我一下
You look stiff, Dad! You should smile wider, too, Kakeru.
爸，你太僵硬了
Say cheese!
笑一個
-Smile! -Got it.
-微笑 -知道了
I'll compile these into an album for you, Kii.
希衣，我再整理成相簿給妳
-Really? -Yes.
-真的嗎？ -對呀
Didn't you say you don't want to take any photos?
妳不是說妳再也不想拍照了？
-You sure look excited. -Shut up.
-妳看起來很興奮啊 -吵死了
Have you written the card?
你卡片寫好了沒？
Ta-dah!
你們看！
"Next time, give the old hag from the next door a good punch, too!"
“下次連隔壁的老太婆一起打！”
Got it. I'll do my best!
我知道了，我會用力的！
Hey, give me a break!
喂，饒了我吧！
-No, that old hag-- -Sorry to keep everyone waiting.
-不，那個老太婆… -抱歉久等了
It's stewed meat and potatoes!
是馬鈴薯燉肉耶！
-We're digging in! -Thank you for the food.
-我開動了！
This taste…
這個味道…
It tastes just like Mom's cooking.
是媽媽的味道
Mita. How did you make this?
三田小姐，妳怎麼做到的？
It is the responsibility of a housekeeper to remember the household's taste buds.
家政婦的職責 就是要記住家裡的味道
Mom's cooking…
媽媽的料理…
It tasted this good.
就跟這個一樣美味呢
It's tasty!
好好吃！
Wow, Kii! You ate it!
哇，希衣，妳把番茄吃掉了
Tomatoes contain lycopene and helps prevent cancer.
番茄的茄紅素可以抗癌唷
Who cares about that?
誰在乎呀？
Isn't it tasty?
好不好吃？
-Well done, Kii! -You're doing great, Kii!
-好棒喔，希衣 -希衣，妳好厲害
Mr. Asuda.
主人
May I leave for the day?
我可以下班了嗎？
Right…
對…
Yes.
可以
Mita…
三田小姐…
Thank you for everything today.
今天真的謝謝妳了
About what?
關於什麼？
Oh, well…
這個…
Thanks to you,
多虧了妳
it felt as if the kids were able to pour out
孩子們才能在失去母親之後
all the feelings they bottled up
將所有壓抑的情緒
ever since their mother passed away.
全都發洩出來
This is the invoice.
這是收據
What?
什麼？
I will need to charge you for two hours of overtime work today.
我要跟您申請今天加班兩小時的薪水
Okay.
好
Please excuse me.
我先走了
Mita!
三田小姐
My wife didn't die in an accident.
我太太不是死於意外
She committed suicide.
她是自殺的
She died because of me.
她是因為我才會死的
I wonder when he'll be back.
我好奇他什麼時候才會回來
What are you doing?
你在幹嘛？
Nothing.
沒幹嘛
You loved apples, didn't you?
妳喜歡蘋果，對吧？
Is that all you have to say?
你只是要說這個嗎？
What?
什麼？
Please excuse me.
我先走了
Why was Mom at the river that day?
媽媽那天為什麼在河邊？
You're not being bullied, are you?
-你是不是被霸凌啊？ -三田小姐，妳什麼事都願意做嗎？
What are you doing to a child?
妳對一個孩子做了什麼？
I was trying to punish him.
我想要懲罰他
Could you kill him for me?
妳可以幫我殺了他嗎？
As you wish.
我知道了